Rabi C Shah

green.rabi@hotmail.com

http://rabi.info
github: @rabishah

I am a front end engineer, confident in molding ideas into scalable production systems. I've worked extensively in teams and alone in building web applications to solve realworld problems for the last four years.

Currently, I am working on my personal project named <u>Chapi</u>. It is a <u>personal knowledge</u> <u>management(PKM)</u> tool.

Skills & Expertise

Paradigm and Methodologies	Agile, OOPS, BEM, Modular Programming
Web Technologies	HTML, CSS, Javascript and Node
UI Libraries / Framework	React, Vue and Angular
Application Architecture	Flux, MVC, MVVM
Hybrid Mobile Frameworks	Ionic and Phonegap
Tools	Wireframing, AWS, Git and Shell

Work Experiences

BAXI: The Bike Taxi http://baxi.taxi

Oct 2015 - Nov 2016

At Baxi, as a Senior Software Developer, I was responsible for developing and maintaining scalable web applications for the end users. I had also worked in maintaining immutable infrastructure.

To streamline the process of on boarding drivers and their documents, we chose Parse server modeled on the concept of finite-state-machine and Vue.js for building web components. I introduced Redux as application architecture for the dashboard web application built in ReactJS.

I automated blue-green deployments with AWS Codedeploy, configured different versions of APIs using AWS API Gateway. For near real-time logging of HTTP endpoints, I used AWS Lambda for transporting the logs to visualize and track in logz.io. I named my bot Hobbit (a Hubot) who could deploy our code from Slack.

http://bookmyshow.com

bookmyshow.com

Oct 2015 - Nov 2016

At bookmyshow.com, I was lead user interface developer for React builds, created modular components with Webpack, JSX and CSS Modules.

We built an event management platform for Meetings, Incentives, Conferences and Events (MICE) which included ticketing, payments and templates with just-in-time compilation. I called my bundler 'chetta' which provided a black box environment for building web components in isolation from the app.

Web Hacker http://minsh.com

Oct 2015 - Nov 2016

As a Web Hacker in Minsh, I worked with a jolly team in bringing a hybrid mobile web application for Community Engagement from idea to production. The app is used by @BangaloreJS community and many more clients.

I gained valuable experience in project ownership, server side and client side development, code testing (unit & end-to-end). I also contributed in building a bower component angular-errors-directive. It is a user error feedback directive for Angular.js

Personal Projects



Chapi - save everything from web

http://chapi.27ae60.com



los mangos for radfadmad

http://radfadmad.com



Shrii - a transliterator from English to Nepali

https://rabishah.github.io/nepali-unicode

Publications

Semantic Web in Medical Information System

IJAET Journals 2012

Graph Database Model for Querying, Searching and Updating ICSCA 2012. IPCSIT vol. 41 IACSIT Press. Singapore.

Education & Interests

Bachelor Of Information Technology

Indian Institute of Information Technology Allahabad, India 2009 - 2013

- * Actively involved in communities like <u>BangaloreJS</u>, <u>KathmanduJS</u>, <u>Code for Nepal</u> and <u>Developers Nepal</u>.
- * Volunteered for non profit organizations: <u>Youth Action of Nepal</u>, <u>Youth Initiative (YI)</u> and <u>Nepal Japan Children Library (NJCL)</u>.
- * Travelling, Reading books and mangas, Playing games, watching football (Premier League).